James Hubert Price Papers WLU.Coll.0090
Washington and Lee University, University Library Special Collections and Archives
James Hubert Price Papers
Inclusive 1927-1943
Washington and Lee University, University Library Special Collections and Archives
Price, James H. (James Hubert)
WLU.Coll.0090
2.5 Linear Feet 2.5 (linear feet.)
Box 1-7
Folder 1-98
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research use.
Biographical / Historical
James H. Price was a member of the Washington and Lee University School of Law, Class of 1909, and the governor of Virginia from 1938-1942.
Scope and Contents
The papers of James H. Price, Governor of Virginia (1938-1942), including correspondence during his gubernatorial years; addresses to the General Assembly and of various organizations; radio speeches to the people of Virginia; World War II Virginia civil defense materials; photographs.
Speeches, addresses, etc., American; Photographs; World War (1939-1945); Civil defense; Virginia; Governors; Political science; Correspondence; Virginia. General Assembly
- Correspondence, 1927-1942 (Box 1-4)
  - Correspondence, 1926-08-1938-03 (Box 1, Folder 1-19)
    - Control Folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1926-08-26-1927-09-02 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1927-09-03-1927-09-06 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1927-09-06-1927-09-07 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1927-09-07-1927-09-09 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1927-09-10-1927-09-19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1927-09-21-1927-10-01 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1927-10-03-1930-10-03 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1935 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1936-1937-08-06 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1937-08-09-1937-08-26 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1937-08-26-1937-08-31 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1937-09-1937-11-10 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1937-11-11-1937-12-15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1937-12-17-1938-01-13 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1938-01-14-1938-01-31 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1938-02-01-1938-02-05 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1938-02-07-1938-02-16 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1938-02-16-1938-02-22 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1938-02-23-1938-03-01 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1938-03-1939-08 (Box 2, Folder 21-40)
    - Correspondence, 1938-03-02-1938-03-07 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1938-03-08-1938-03-10 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1938-03-11-1938-03-15 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1938-03-16-1938-03-18 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1938-03-18-1938-03-22 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1938-03-23-1938-03-31 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1938-04-01-1938-04-05 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1938-04-06-1938-04-14 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1938-04-15-1938-04-30 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, 1938-05-02-1938-05-14 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1938-04-15-1938-04-30 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1938-06-01-1938-06-25 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, 1938-06-27-1938-07-13 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence, 1938-07-14-1938-08-04 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, 1938-08-08-1938-08-26 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, 1938-08-27-1938-09-27 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence, 1938-10-01-1938-11-16 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence, 1938-11-17-1938-12-27 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, 1939-01 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, 1939-02-01-1939-02-08 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence, 1938-03-02-1938-03-07 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1939-02-1940-05 (Box 3, Folder 41-58)
    - Correspondence, 1939-02-09-1939-02-11 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence, 1939-02-12-1939-02-28 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence, 1939-03 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence, 1939-04 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence, 1939-05 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence, 1939-06-1939-07-21 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence, 1939-07-22-1939-07-26 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence, 1939-07-27-1939-08-04 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence, 1939-08-05-1939-08-11 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Correspondence, 1939-08-14-1939-09-11 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence, 1939-09-12-1939-10 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Correspondence, 1939-11 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Correspondence, 1939-12 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence, 1940-01-1940-02-07 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence, 1940-02-08-1940-03-11 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Correspondence, 1940-03-12-1940-03-15 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence, 1940-03-18-1940-04-15 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Correspondence, 1940-04-17-1940-05-04 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, 1940-05-1942 (Box 4, Folder 59-74)
    - Correspondence, 1940-05-07-1940-05-31 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Correspondence, 1940-06 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Correspondence, 1940-07-01-1940-07-25 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Correspondence, 1940-07-26-1940-08-12 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Correspondence, 1940-08-13-1940-09-09 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Correspondence, 1940-09-10-1940-10 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Correspondence, 1940-11-1940-12-04 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Correspondence, 1940-12-07-1940-12-31 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Correspondence, 1941-01-1941-04 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Correspondence, 1941-05-1941-06 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Correspondence, 1941-07-1941-08 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Correspondence, 1941-09-1941-12 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Correspondence, 1942-01 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Correspondence, 1942-02 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Correspondence, 1942-03-1942-05 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Correspondence, 1927-1942 (Box 4, Folder 74)
- Speeches, 1930-1941 (Box 5-6, Folder 75-93)
  - Speeches, 1930-1940-12 (Box 5, Folder 75-81)
  - Speeches, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 82-93)
- Government documents, miscellaneous papers, and printed matter (Box 7, Folder 94-98)
  - Virginia Civil Defense Manuals, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - Virginia General Assembly papers, 1940